

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Cloud (Azure)
Windows Server (2003 - 2019)
Virtualization (Hyper-V, VirtualBox)
SQL (Microsoft SQL Server)
Web Server (IIS)
Windows, Mac, and Linux OS
Firewall and Security (Fortigate)
Office 365
Programming (VB.NET and C#)
Web Development (HTML, CSS, JS, WP, GIT, Bootstrap)
Enterprise-Class Antivirus Solutions
Networking
iOS and Android OS

PERSONAL SKILLS

Jira and Confluence Service Desk

Reliable and professional
Organized
Time management
Team player
Fast learner
Motivated
Capability of Analysis
Problem Solving

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native English: Fluent

CONTACT

(438) 372-3351 OrlandoReynoso1983@gmail.com www.OrlandoReynoso.net LinkedIn

REFERENCES

Available upon request

ORLANDO REYNOSO

IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

HIGHLIGHTS: Successful IT support and system administrator with more than 16 years of experience in the field. always stimulating myself and coworkers to work hard looking to achieve beyond the expected results refreshing knowledge and creativity. My collaborative leadership, persuasive skills, my positive attitude, and my solid work ethic have allowed me to obtain solid knowledge in many technologies and teamwork. I can prioritize, work under pressure, and meet deadlines. I am always highly motivated to learn new things from everyone around me. Seeking to use my expertise, skills, and abilities to contribute to your organization's success.

EXPERIENCE

APPLICATION SUPPORT ENGINEER

VISIUMKMS | 2020 - 2022

Managing ticket workload, escalating issues where appropriate and providing resolution to issues. Liaising with internal Customer Managers, Service Desk, Incident and Problem Managers and Change Managers, whilst being involved in the management of major incidents and performance reporting. Troubleshooting issues in the product (application and data), Ensuring reviews are fully documented, Being involved in changes to the service operation tools, processes and working practices. Coordinating with Delivery (Product Development) and Implementation teams to support product updates. Creating Microsoft SQL Server and Oracle Databases scripts to identify and correct data integrity issues in customer's data.

Technologies and Tools: Windows OS, Microsoft and Oracle DB, Windows Server 2019, HTML, CSS and JS, Chrome Developer Tools, Networking, IIS, Azure, Version Control System GIT, VS Code, Remote Desktop, Microsoft Teams, Office 365, Jira and Confluence Service Desk, iOS, Android OS.

IT SUPPORT MANAGER AND SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

MEPyD | 2013 - 2020

Worked as Windows System Administrator 2012/2016 servers, AD, GPO, DNS, DHCP, NAS storage, backup system, print server, virtualization, surveillance system, local network, Wi-Fi system, shared access, and Office. Worked with about 200 Windows 7, 8.1 and 10 computers inventory. Security with firewall FortiGate UTM (Antivirus, Web Filter, Application Control, Email Filter, Instruction Protection, Traffic Shaper, etc.) Manager of 7 technicians in the technology department to provide quality service.

Collaborated on developing systems Client - Server using VB.Net and SQL Server 2012.

Technologies: Windows, Mac, and Linux Operating Systems, Windows Server: Active Directory, Group Policy, DHCP, and DNS, Computer Hardware and Software, Cisco Meraki Wi-Fi System, Office 365, NAS Storage, United Threat Management appliance - UTM - FortiGate, Hyper-V, Printers, Surveillance and Access Control Systems, Programming: VB.Net and SQL.

IT SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

CENTRO MEDICO SANTIAGO APOSTOL | 2009 - 2013

Managed, configured and troubleshooted computers, networks, information systems, databases, and ensured related issues to information technology worked effectively. Provided to our customers or user the best experience posible using our computer and systems.

Technologies: Windows Operative System, Windows Server: Active Directory, Group Policy, and DHCP, Security and Acceleration Server (ISA Server), Microsoft SQL Server, Print server, Computer Hardware and Software, LAN and WIFI Networking, MS Office.

SYSTEM TECHNICIAN

COMPUNET | 2007 - 2009

Configured and troubleshot employee attendance systems and card printers. Managed the local network company and its information systems, Windows Server 2003, GPO, AD, and computers.

Technologies: Windows Operative System, Windows Server: Active Directory, LAN Networking, Computer Hardware and Software, Biometric attendance Systems, ID Card Printers.

SYSTEM SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

ARS-CMD | 2004 - 2007

Provided professional assistance configuring and troubleshooting our local network, information systems, servers, printer and computers.

Technologies: Windows Operative System, Windows Server: Active Directory and Group Policy, LAN Networking, Computer Hardware and Software, Security and Acceleration Server (ISA Server).

EDUCATION

BACHELOR IN BUSINESS INFORMATICS | SUMMA CUM LAUDE

UNIVERSIDAD ABIERTA PARA ADULTOS (UAPA), Santiago, D.R. 2011 - 2015